Speaker 1: Our
Speaker 2: guest, Congressman Davidson, is an army veteran, including service with the old guard here in the nation's capitals. I wanted to get your thoughts on the chair of the Joint Chiefs and a story in the Washington Post this morning about a briefing yesterday. Pentagon officials on Wednesday defended the military's tradition of staying out of elections after a new book reported
Speaker 3: that General Mark Milley, the chair of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, feared that President Donald Trump would
attempt a coup.
Yeah, I've
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): been a little concerned about General Milley as chairman of the Joint Chiefs. I mean, I suppose he fits just fine for what Biden's trying to do. He's politicized the military from the beginning. Right now, I'm on the board of visitors for the United States Military Academy, and we haven't been able to meet since Joe Biden became president.
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): So why, they suspended it because they were concerned the military was being politicized. The reality is they're working to politicize the military and they're preventing anyone from being able to be present as they do it, including members of Congress. So I'm very concerned about what Joe Biden's doing as commander in chief, what his secretary of defense, Lloyd Austin, is doing.
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): and now, sadly, what uniformed military officers are doing to politicize the military. I was very concerned by General Milley's idea that President Trump being able to say, "Look, we are going to control this street. "We're going to push back people on this block," saying somehow he was embarrassed to be part of that. That is, in fact, the role. I mean, my own dad in the '60s was deployed from Fort Bragg, North Carolina up to Andrews Air Force Base the last time the military was brought in to help us
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): to establish security. Now these were protests right after George Floyd, not after January 6th, and there were some other things the President did that people, I think, rightly had some concerns about politicizing, but the idea that the nation's military would be used to secure the capital isn't controversial, and it certainly wasn't controversial on Inauguration Day and for two or three months afterwards as Fort Pelosi was erected here at the Capitol. So I am very concerned that the military is being with a size
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): at every level under this administration, and it seems like General Milley seems okay with it as long as the political tune is going to the left.
This is
Speaker 5: Marion calling from Groveton, Georgia, Democrats' line. Hi,
thanks for
Speaker 6: taking my call.
Speaker 7: Representative Davidson, you're from Ohio. My first question, how long have you been in office? I came
in the summer
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): of June 16th. I came in in a special election because John Boehner, when he was Speaker of the House, not only did
Speaker 8: he
resign his
Speaker 8: He resigned as our member of Congress. So we had a special election. The primary was in March of '16. And then in June of '16, we
had a
Speaker 9: special. - Okay, June '16. Okay, then you've been there
Speaker 10: long enough. I have been reading, and this is a little off what the everyday stuff we're talking
Speaker 11: about. In the last 20 years, we've gone from 15 million to 30 million acres,
Speaker 11: land, farmland, that is now being owned by other countries in our country. In other words, we've gone from 15 million to 30 million in 20 years of land owned by foreigners, and this is prime farmland. Ohio and Texas has no restrictions, and states can actually restrict how much land
Speaker 12: foreigners in their states can own. Iowa, nobody owns any and no foreigners own any land in Iowa. So if you're in Ohio and you're so worried about foreigners of illegals coming in, why aren't
Speaker 11: you worried about foreign investors coming in and buying up unlimited amount of
Speaker 10: prime agricultural land in your state?
Speaker 10: And that's my question, thank
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): you. - It's a good question. You know, you've already drawn the conclusion that I'm not worried about it, which is false. So during, you know, the previous Congress, a couple Congresses ago when Republicans were in the majority, we passed the Foreign Investment Risk Reduction Modernization Act. That's a, you know, big cluster of letters. But there's a committee on foreign investment in the U.S. It was strengthened. One of the big pieces that was strengthened, and that was to review
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): Real estate purchases. So China in particular is purchasing real estate, not just farm land, but when they can't acquire sensitive technology sometimes they'll buy the whole office building that something they want to acquire is in and then try to, you know, use the building's infrastructure to steal the data. So we should rightly have concerns that real estate would be a way for foreign influence to grow in the United States.
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): Under Republican leadership, bills were passed to do that. And I think you're right to say we should use a more holistic approach for the federal government and state governments to review this. And I think people have been slow to respond to foreign purchases of real estate.
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): uh... in this kind of review process um... that was intended to be addressed by firma but the other thing is we've been slow to respond to china broadly uh... i would greatly appreciate donald trump putting the emphasis on trade being an ohio guy and a manufacturing guy uh... this was long overdue our manufacturing sector in particular was being crushed
by
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): China's practices and my hope is that we can build a broader coalition to deal with China's abuse. They promised to be a market-based economy as part of being in the World Trade Organization and they have not done that. They steal intellectual property, they shape market access, they don't subsidize product in that really accelerates their abuse of stolen intellectual property.
Speaker 4 (lower-pitched voice): and so it is very anti-competitive and they don't just do it to the United States they do it to everyone so my hope is that we can build a coalition around the world that forces China to behave differently in particular but there are other concerns about real estate purchases and so thanks